GARY BOWEN

Software Engineer

813-666-9680 • garybowen2021@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/garybowen-6b172a208/ • https://github.com/gjrocky

Summary

With over three years as a software engineer, I'm looking to advance my career further in big data. I'm captivated by the power of data when it comes to the domains of Media, Finance and Tech as a whole. While Working at Nielsen and Florida State University, I've seen how data can drive decisions and innovation, and I want to be at the forefront of all of these exciting fields.

TECH STACK

Python · SQL · Java · PowerBI · Prometheus · C++ · Java Spark · C · C# · Javascript · MIPS · Docker · Linux · Data Bricks · GCP · Trino

Terraform · AWS · Kubernetes · Airflow · Manta · Datadog · Django · Reactjs · Nodejs · Hadoop · Apache Spark · Grafana · React Native · CI/CD

Education

Florida State University

BS: Computer Science 05/2017 - 04/2021

Eastern University

MS: Data Science 2024 - Present

Experience

Software Engineer Intern

Tampa, FL

Maria de la companya de la companya

Nielsen 06/2021 - 08/2021

- Actively collaborated with the team in leveraging SQL and PowerBI to create efficient and visually informative dashboards. These dashboards
 played a pivotal role in providing key insights to the organization.
- Successfully cooperated with my colleagues to implement optimization strategies for SQL queries, resulting in a remarkable 30-second
 reduction in dashboard load times. This improvement significantly enhanced user experience and enabled quicker decision-making.

Software Engineer - Data Engineer

Nielsen

Tampa, FL 08/2021 - Present

- Worked with a diverse range of technology stacks, including Airflow, Terraform, Java Spark, Kubernetes, AWS, Datadog, and Manta, Python, C, C++.
- Managed, analyzed, and aggregated large datasets using DynamoDB. Using various Data Engineering techniques, I managed, processed and built data driven models in Python, C++, and Java for various major media companies such as Amazon, Netflix, Hulu, Disney + etc.
- Automated various critical processes, such as unit testing, job deployment, and job monitoring using Airflow, Kubernetes, Python, Java Spark, and GitLab CI/CD, AWS S3, AWS Lambda, and AWS Secret Manager. These automations have significantly enhanced efficiency and reduced the margin for error in our operations.
- Contributed to the management, analysis, and aggregation of Amazon's TNF (Thursday Night Football) Data. This involvement has provided me with a deep understanding of handling substantial datasets and extracting meaningful information to support decision-making processes.
- Integrated Machine Learning processes and wrote data models with Python to improve production monitoring and data prediction, which now allows us to error check issues in the data we receive realtime.
- Migrated the entire codebase 3 times from Java, Jenkins, AWS, AWS EC2, to Java, Java Spark, Kubernetes and Airflow to Python, Airflow, and Kubernetes, to keep dev ops up to date.
- Worked with multiple dev ops tools to facilitate our jobs. These tools included GitLab CI/CD, Kubernetes, Airflow, Terraform, AWS, GCP, Trino, Spark, and Hadoop.

Florida State University

Tallahassee, FL

Web Developer

08/2019 - 04/2021

- Served as a key contributor, I led the team in comprehensive project and web strategic planning tailored to the needs of Student Health
 Services. My strategic planning and user-focused design improvements led to an impressive 20% increase in department website efficiency,
 resulting in quicker access to vital information for both students and staff.
- Regularly reviewed and maintained the accuracy and functionality of information and elements across various websites and pages. This meticulous attention to detail was vital in a healthcare setting like Student Health Services, where information accuracy directly impacted patient trust and satisfaction.
- Built and Maintained FSU Health website backends using Python/Django and designed these webpages with CSS and HTML.
- Started the initial codebase changes towards using ReactJS instead of Django.